A Guide to the Lake Drummond Home Demonstration Club (Chesapeake, Va.) Records, 1950-1976
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Lake Drummond Home Demonstration Club (Chesapeake, Va.) Records, 1950-1976
The Library of Virginia
51761
.9 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Lake Drummond Baptist Church, Chesapeake.
Historical Information
In the summer of 1910, Miss Ella G. Agnew was made "State Agent for Girls' Tomato Clubs," by Dr. Seaman A. Knapp (1831-1911), under the auspices of the General Education Board. Agnew began to work with girls in Halifax and Nottoway Counties who planted tomatoes, cared for them, and preserved their fruit. Thus, the foundation was laid for home demonstration work in Virginia. The tomato clubs eventually became known as canning clubs, and enlisted other members of the family and gradually began to influence other phases of homemaking. In 1914, the Smith-Lever Act was passed by Congress, providing funds for cooperative extension work in agriculture and home economics. Home demonstration work made a steady growth in Virginia from 1914 to 1917 in the number of agents employed and counties affected, and also in broadening programs. The Lake Drummond Home Demonstration Club was organized "to foster the highest ideas of home life, and to provide members with the opportunity to work with the Home Demonstration Agent and the Extenstion Division of the Virginia Polytechnic Institute in a city-wide program for the development and improvement of home and community life, and affiliation with the Virginia Federation of Home Demonstration Clubs in a state-wide program."
Scope and Content
Records, 1950-1976, of the Lake Drummond Home Demonstration Club in Chesapeake, Virginia, including certificates, constitutions and by-laws, financial reports, membership lists, minutes, program material, reports, scrapbook, and yearbooks.
Contents List
- Certificates. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Chesapeake Home Demonstration Clubs. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Constitutions and By-Laws. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The Countrywoman (1969). (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Fairs and Exhibitions. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Financial Reports. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Membership Lists. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Minutes, December 1950 - November 1954. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Minutes, January 1960 - May 1963. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Minutes, July 1963 - May 1968. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Minutes, 26 March 1970. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- National Home Demonstration Council. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Officers and Project Leaders. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Parliamentary Procedure. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- President's Reports. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Program Material - Embroidery and Sewing. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Program Material - Family. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Program Material - Foreign Cultures. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Program Material - Gardening. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Program Material - Interior Design. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Program Material - Kitchen Design and Care. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Program Material - Meal Preparation. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Program Material - Trees and Forestry. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Program Material - Miscellaneous. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Program Topics and Ideas. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Programs/Agendas. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Reading Lists. (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Scrapbook, 1964-1966. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Thank You Notes. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Travel Club. (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Yearbooks - Chesapeake Home Demonstration Clubs, 1966, 1970-1971. (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Yearbooks - Virginia Federation of Home Demonstration Clubs, 1967-1968, 1971-1972. (Box 2, Folder 12)